<creator>
  <type_identity>
    <type>corporate_body</type>
  </type_identity>
  <name>College van Commissarissen voor Mindere Kwesti&amp;#235;n Cura&amp;#231;ao</name>
  <name_english>Board of Commissioners for Minor Cases on Cura&amp;#231;ao</name_english>
  <begindatum>
    <year>1717</year>
    <month/>
    <day/>
  </begindatum>
  <einddatum>
    <year>1853</year>
    <month/>
    <day/>
  </einddatum>
  <period_description/>
  <his_func>&lt;p&gt;In 1717 it was decided to establish a council of justice for cases up to an amount of 300 pesos (later 600 pesos): the Commissioners of Minor Cases and Disputes, also known as the 'Petty Council'. The council consisted of five commissioners presided over by the Director (Governor) of Cura&amp;#231;ao.The secretary of the island's council also acted as secretary for the commissioners. In 1746 the council was dissolved and replaced by a court consisting of two extra-ordinary Councillors presided over by the fiscal (public prosecutor). But already in 1749 the earlier situation was restored, with a slight change: no longer the Governor, but one of the commissioners would act as president. There was a possibility of appeal to the island's council, or 'Grand Council'. Since 1757 the administration of the commissioners was separated from that of the Grand Council. Consequently, a separate archive was formed.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;During the second British interregnum (1807-1816) new regulations for the Petty Council were issued. The commissioners also became a board of advice to the bailiffs heading the three divisions into which Cura&amp;#231;ao was divided at that time. The bailiffs acted as judges for cases up to 100 pesos. After Dutch rule was restored in 1816, the council was replaced as a court for minor questions by the Board of Commerce and Affairs of the Sea.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In 1828 again a court for minor cases was established, called the 'Board of Minor Cases' and consisting of the president and two Councillors of the Council of Civil and Criminal Justice.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;</his_func>
  <related_archive_title>
    <relation>/data/data_Atlantische_wereld/Archieven/Nationaal_Archief/1_05_12_01_Curacao_tot_1828/HaNA_1_05_12_01</relation>
  </related_archive_title>
  <related_creators>
    <relation>/data/data_Atlantische_wereld/Archiefvormers/Organisaties/Raad_Curacao</relation>
    <relation>/data/data_Atlantische_wereld/Archiefvormers/Organisaties/Raden-commissarissen_tot_het_houden_der_dingtalen</relation>
  </related_creators>
  <link_law/>
  <keyword_geography>
    <geo>curacao</geo>
  </keyword_geography>
  <keyword_subject>
    <subject>courtsofjustice</subject>
  </keyword_subject>
  <keyword_person/>
  <notes></notes>
  <literatuur/>
  <made_by>HJ</made_by>
  <Aantekeningen>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relatie&lt;/strong&gt; met College van Commercie en Zeezaken Curacao.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1834 three members of the court of justice were appointed to act as Commissioners for Minor Cases. This situation lasted until 1853.&lt;/p&gt;</Aantekeningen>
</creator>