<creator>
  <type_identity>
    <type>corporate_body</type>
  </type_identity>
  <name>Financi&amp;#235;le administratie van Cura&amp;#231;ao</name>
  <name_english>Financial administration of Cura&amp;#231;ao</name_english>
  <begindatum>
    <year>1634</year>
    <month/>
    <day/>
  </begindatum>
  <einddatum>
    <year>1834</year>
    <month/>
    <day/>
  </einddatum>
  <period_description/>
  <his_func>From the 17th up to the early 19th century, a number of separate civil servants were entrusted with the collection of taxes and other income of the colony and with the paying of salaries and expenses. At the end of the 18th century a bookkeeper general was appointed. Financial accounts, valuation assessments, etc. were periodically sent to the metropolis. After Cura&amp;#231;ao and its dependencies Aruba and Bonaire came under Dutch rule again in 1816, a Councillor comptroller-general (raad contrarolleur-generaal) was appointed. All the colonial civil servants responsible for collecting and controlling monies (taxes, levies, etc.), like the tax collector general, the warehouse keeper, the auction master, the weigh-house master, the Commanders of Aruba and Bonaire, were responsible to him. The Councillor comptroller-general was also responsible for the colonial warehouses. In 1828 the general financial management was entrusted to a bookkeeper-comptroller. He also supervised and controlled the colonial financial officers and the colonial warehouses. In 1833 the colonial bookkeeping was kept by a financial administrator, supervised by the Governor.</his_func>
  <related_archive_title>
    <relation>/data/data_Atlantische_wereld/Archieven/Nationaal_Archief/1_05_12_01_Curacao_tot_1828/HaNA_1_05_12_01</relation>
    <relation>/data/data_Atlantische_wereld/Archieven/Nationaal_Archief/1_05_12_02_Curacao_na_1828/HaNA_1_05_12_02</relation>
    <relation>/data/data_Atlantische_wereld/Archieven/Nationaal_Archief_Curacao/archief_van_het_gouvernement_of_koloniaal_archief/Archief_van_het_gouvernement</relation>
  </related_archive_title>
  <related_creators/>
  <link_law/>
  <keyword_geography>
    <geo>curacao</geo>
  </keyword_geography>
  <keyword_subject>
    <subject>civilandpoliticaladministration</subject>
    <subject>taxes</subject>
  </keyword_subject>
  <keyword_person/>
  <notes></notes>
  <literatuur/>
  <made_by>HJ</made_by>
  <Aantekeningen/>
</creator>