<creator>
  <type_identity>
    <type>corporate_body</type>
  </type_identity>
  <name>Raden / Hoven van politie en van justitie / fiscaal van Suriname</name>
  <name_english>Councillors / Councils of Policy and Justice / fiscal of Suriname</name_english>
  <begindatum>
    <year>1669</year>
    <month/>
    <day/>
  </begindatum>
  <einddatum>
    <year/>
    <month/>
    <day/>
  </einddatum>
  <period_description/>
  <his_func>&lt;p&gt;In the 17th - 19th centuries, the names of the institutions were as follows: Political Council (or Council of Policy) 1669-1680; Council of Policy and Justice 1680-1683; Council of Policy and Criminal Justice 1684-1828; and Judicial Council 1669-1689; Council of Civil Justice 1689-1828.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Governor was assisted by a political council. This body consisted of ten of the most prominent settlers, who were appointed for life by the Governor. The Commander of the troops and the fiscal took part in this Council, both in an advisory capacity. The Council had a secretary. Governor and Councillors also practised criminal law. In general, the Council held an ordinary meeting four times a year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The authority of the council changed in the 19th century, after the restoration of Dutch rule in 1816. A lifetime appointment for a settler member turned into a period of nine years. In 1828 the Council of Policy was replaced by the High Council of the Netherlands West Indian Possessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The administration of civil law and the supervision of the Orphans Chamber rested with the Council of Civil Justice. The Governor was a member as well as six settlers elected from their own group. The Council decided by majority vote. Minor disputes were settled in the Board of Commissioners for Minor Cases. With the establishment of a Council of Civil and Criminal Justice in 1828, the Council of Civil Justice was abolished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The function of a fiscal (Public Prosecutor) existed from 1683 until 1828 with the introduction of the newly established post of Attorney General. Among the Governor and Councillors the fiscal was often the only lawyer.&lt;/p&gt;</his_func>
  <related_archive_title>
    <relation>/data/data_Atlantische_wereld/Archieven/Nationaal_Archief/1_05_10_02_Suriname_tot_1828_Raad_van_Politie/HaNA_1_05_10_02</relation>
    <relation>/data/data_Atlantische_wereld/Archieven/Nationaal_Archief/1_05_10_04_Suriname_tot_1828_Raad_van_Justitie/HaNA_1_05_10_04</relation>
  </related_archive_title>
  <related_creators/>
  <link_law/>
  <keyword_geography>
    <geo>suriname</geo>
  </keyword_geography>
  <keyword_subject>
    <subject>civilandpoliticaladministration</subject>
    <subject>courtsofjustice</subject>
  </keyword_subject>
  <keyword_person/>
  <notes/>
  <literatuur/>
  <made_by>MS</made_by>
  <Aantekeningen>&lt;p&gt;zelf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pilot, p.9 en Actoren Suriname, p. 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enc.N.W.Indie (1981), p. 303.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buddingh', p. 33&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vink, Creole jews, p. 70-71.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gesch. Suriname, p. 31-33.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roessingh, Guide, p. 65-66.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HaNA, 1.05.10.02 (inleiding), 1.05.10.04 (inleiding); zie ook 1.05.11.02, 1.05.11.03, 1.05.11.04.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hartsinck, p. 895-986 lijst van raden-fiscaal&lt;/p&gt;</Aantekeningen>
</creator>