<creator>
  <type_identity>
    <type>corporate_body</type>
  </type_identity>
  <name>Raad van Civiele en Criminele Justitie / Rechtbank / College (Commissarissen) van Kleine Zaken van St. Eustatius en Saba</name>
  <name_english>Council of Civil and Criminal Justice / Court of Justice / Board (Commissioners) for Minor Cases on St Eustatius and Saba</name_english>
  <begindatum>
    <year>1683</year>
    <month/>
    <day/>
  </begindatum>
  <einddatum>
    <year/>
    <month/>
    <day/>
  </einddatum>
  <period_description/>
  <his_func>&lt;p&gt;The Commander of St Eustatius presided over a Council that consisted of six members. The Councillors were appointed by the Commander from a nomination drawn up by the citizens. The Council acted both as a body of government and as a court of law. During the French occupation of 1781-1784 and the two British interregnums (1801-1802; 1810-1816), the Council remained in function. In 1816 two separate councils were installed: a Court of Policy and a Court of Justice. The former consisted of the Governor, the bookkeeper general and five citizen representatives. The Council of Justice had five members. With the reorganization of the government of the Dutch Caribbean colonies in 1828, the Court of Policy was replaced by a municipal council consisting of two aldermen and four members, presided over by the Commander and administratively supported by the secretary. The first alderman was entrusted with the general government and acted as a Public Prosecutor. The second alderman supervised the finances of the colony and acted as president of the Orphans Chamber. The administration of justice remained with a Council of Civil and Criminal Justice, consisting of two civil servants, and four citizens (two landowners and two merchants). In 1834 the municipal council was replaced by a Colonial Council consisting of six representatives of the citizens. The administration of justice was now entrusted to a Court of Justice for St Eustatius and Saba.&lt;/p&gt;</his_func>
  <related_archive_title>
    <relation>/data/data_Atlantische_wereld/Archieven/Nationaal_Archief/1_05_13_01_St_Eustatius_St_Maarten_en_Saba_tot_1828/HaNA_1_05_13_01</relation>
    <relation>/data/data_Atlantische_wereld/Archieven/Nationaal_Archief/1_05_13_02_St_Eustatius_en_Saba_na_1828/HaNA_01_05_13_02</relation>
    <relation>/data/data_Atlantische_wereld/Archieven/Nationaal_Archief_Curacao/St_Eustatius/St_Eustatius</relation>
  </related_archive_title>
  <related_creators>
    <relation>/data/data_Atlantische_wereld/Archiefvormers/Organisaties/Gouverneur_St_Eustatius</relation>
    <relation>/data/data_Atlantische_wereld/Archiefvormers/Organisaties/Gezaghebber_St_Eustatius_en_Saba</relation>
  </related_creators>
  <link_law/>
  <keyword_geography>
    <geo>st_eustatius</geo>
  </keyword_geography>
  <keyword_subject>
    <subject>courtsofjustice</subject>
  </keyword_subject>
  <keyword_person/>
  <notes/>
  <literatuur/>
  <made_by>HJ</made_by>
  <Aantekeningen/>
</creator>