<archiefmat>
  <rf_country>
    <country>SR</country>
  </rf_country>
  <rf_archive>NASR</rf_archive>
  <ref_code>9.01.01</ref_code>
  <code_subfonds/>
  <series>1-794</series>
  <itemno/>
  <titel>Besluiten van de Gouverneur (zgn. "Protocollen")</titel>
  <titel_eng>Decisions taken by the Governor (the so-called "Protocols")</titel_eng>
  <begindatum>
    <year>1846</year>
    <month/>
    <day/>
  </begindatum>
  <einddatum>
    <year>1872</year>
    <month/>
    <day/>
  </einddatum>
  <period_description/>
  <extent>794 volumes</extent>
  <overhead_title>
    <relation>/data/data_Atlantische_wereld/Archieven/Nationaal_Archief_Suriname/9_01_01_Gouverneur_van_Suriname/NASR_9_01_01</relation>
  </overhead_title>
  <finding_aid/>
  <creator/>
  <scope>&lt;p&gt;Contains resolutions taken by the Governor with appendices (dispatches and papers received; copies of outgoing letters) regarding any conceivable subject relating to maintenance of public order, administration of justice, defense, public health, civil and military personnel, maintenance government buildings etc. (see for subject also the &lt;a href="/atlantischewereld/data/oldaccess-data/Nationaal_Archief_Suriname/9_01_01_Gouverneur_van_Suriname/9_01_01_13960-14267" target="_blank" mce_href="/atlantischewereld/data/oldaccess-data/Nationaal_Archief_Suriname/9_01_01_Gouverneur_van_Suriname/9_01_01_13960-14267"&gt;Agenda's van ingekomen stukken&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="/atlantischewereld/data/oldaccess-data/Nationaal_Archief_Suriname/9_01_01_Gouverneur_van_Suriname/9_01_01_14268-14393" target="_blank" mce_href="/atlantischewereld/data/oldaccess-data/Nationaal_Archief_Suriname/9_01_01_Gouverneur_van_Suriname/9_01_01_14268-14393"&gt;Indices op de protocollen en resoluties en op de journalen&lt;/a&gt;) On the appendices it is usually recorded to which resolution (referred to with the number of the resolution) these documents are related. Documents that were received but are not related to any specific resolution, like for instance weekly returns of prisoners in fort Zeelandia and of punished slaves, are bound together in the second part of the volumes. But these documents can also be found in the series of &lt;a href="/atlantischewereld/data/oldaccess-data/Nationaal_Archief_Suriname/9_01_01_Gouverneur_van_Suriname/NASR_9_01_01_14394-14425" mce_href="/atlantischewereld/data/oldaccess-data/Nationaal_Archief_Suriname/9_01_01_Gouverneur_van_Suriname/NASR_9_01_01_14394-14425"&gt;Ingekomen stukken&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certain resolutions, especially those regarding sensitive subjects, were bound in a separate series of '&lt;a href="/atlantischewereld/data/oldaccess-data/Nationaal_Archief_Suriname/9_01_01_Gouverneur_van_Suriname/9_01_01_12358-12650" target="_blank" mce_href="/atlantischewereld/data/oldaccess-data/Nationaal_Archief_Suriname/9_01_01_Gouverneur_van_Suriname/9_01_01_12358-12650"&gt;Secret resolutions&lt;/a&gt;' (see inventory nos. 12358-12650). The resolutions can also be found in the series of &lt;a href="/atlantischewereld/data/oldaccess-data/Nationaal_Archief_Suriname/9_01_01_Gouverneur_van_Suriname/9_01_01_12800-13550" target="_blank" mce_href="/atlantischewereld/data/oldaccess-data/Nationaal_Archief_Suriname/9_01_01_Gouverneur_van_Suriname/9_01_01_12800-13550"&gt;Journals of the Governor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the period 1846-1848 the protocols are ordered according to number (each new year starting with no. 1).During the period 1849-1852 all decisions regarding the same subject or dispatched by the same authority (garrison; Government Secretary; colonisation; Court of Justice; militia etc.) were gathered in one volume and ordered chronologically on the date of the resolution per month; an agenda of received letters and papers was added. During the perod 1853-1857 the ordering was again according the number of the resolution. Between 1858 and 1882 the protocols were bound according to archival number which was also the number of the resolution. For this period the resolutions are accessible through the agendas of received letters and papers (see inventory nos 13960-14267) and through indices (see inventory nos. 14327-14472).&lt;/p&gt;</scope>
  <undelying_levels_titels/>
  <related_units/>
  <link_law/>
  <keyword_geography>
    <geo>suriname</geo>
  </keyword_geography>
  <keyword_subject>
    <subject>civilandpoliticaladministration</subject>
    <subject>courtsofjustice</subject>
    <subject>law_and_order</subject>
    <subject>legislation</subject>
    <subject>military_personnel</subject>
    <subject>social_and_health_care</subject>
  </keyword_subject>
  <keyword_person/>
  <notes>&lt;p&gt;The complete series up to 1882 consists of 1027 volumes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The numbers of the inventory items may be changed (November 2008).&lt;/p&gt;</notes>
  <made_by>HJ</made_by>
  <Aantekeningen>&lt;p&gt;NB de nummering kan mogelijk nog wijzigen; het archief wordt op dit moment (november 2008) omgenummerd. Later nazien!&lt;/p&gt;</Aantekeningen>
</archiefmat>