<archiefmat>
  <rf_country>
    <country>NL</country>
    <country>SR</country>
  </rf_country>
  <rf_archive>EBGS/HUA</rf_archive>
  <ref_code>212</ref_code>
  <code_subfonds/>
  <series/>
  <itemno/>
  <titel>Inventaris van het in Het Utrechts Archief berustende gedeelte van het archief van de Evangelische Broedergemeente in Suriname</titel>
  <titel_eng>Inventory of a part of the archive of the Evangelical Brotherhood in Suriname, deposited with the Utrecht Archives</titel_eng>
  <begindatum>
    <year>1739</year>
    <month/>
    <day/>
  </begindatum>
  <einddatum>
    <year>1929</year>
    <month/>
    <day/>
  </einddatum>
  <period_description/>
  <extent>717 nos.</extent>
  <overhead_title/>
  <finding_aid/>
  <creator/>
  <scope/>
  <undelying_levels_titels/>
  <related_units>
    <relation>/data/data_Atlantische_wereld/Archieven/Nationaal_Archief/1_05_11_16_Suriname_tot_1828_Burgerlijke_Stand/HaNA_1_05_11_16_22</relation>
  </related_units>
  <link_law/>
  <keyword_geography/>
  <keyword_subject/>
  <keyword_person/>
  <notes>&lt;p&gt;The documents listed in this inventory form only a part of the archive of the Evangelical Brotherhood in Suriname. These documents were shipped to the Netherlands and kept in Het Utrechts Archief (HUA) until October 2006, when they were returned and stored in the archive of the Evangelical Brotherhood in Paramaribo. At the time when information for this archival guide was being gathered in Suriname (2008), the Archive of the Evangelical Brotherhood in Paramaribo was closed, so additional archival material could not be selected. Some of the documents listed in the inventory are in the form of photocopies available in Het Utrechts Archief (HUA).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See also publications of H.E. Lamur.&lt;/p&gt;</notes>
  <made_by>MS</made_by>
  <Aantekeningen>&lt;p&gt;info van het HUA 9 juli 2009: het archief is nog in bewerking; daarom voorlopig de inventaris niet op de website van het HUA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Er zijn in oktober 2006 stukken naar Suriname teruggebracht; er zijn voor deze teruggave stukken gekopieerd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zie Bol/Vrij, p. 133-135, 144-145, 179, invnr. 22 van 1.05.11.16&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nov.-dec. 2009 stukken ingezien, zie het Wordbestand met aantekeningen HUA&lt;/p&gt;</Aantekeningen>
</archiefmat>